Preliminary Inventory to the Ann Wood-Kelly Papers, 1940-2003
Hoover Institution Archives
Ann Wood-Kelly Papers,
1940-2003
97070
Wood-Kelly, Ann
5 manuscript boxes 2.1 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, writings, personnel records, flight logbooks, manuals, newsletters, clippings, other printed matter, and photographs, relating to airplane ferrying operations of the Air Transport Auxiliary in Great Britain during World War II, and to the role of women in aviation.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1997.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Great Britain.--Air Transport Auxiliary.; World War, 1939-1945--Aerial operations.; World War, 1939-1945--Transportation.; World War, 1939-1945--Women.; Women in aeronautics.; Women.; World War, 1939-1945.; Great Britain.; United States--Foreign relations.; Women's Airforce Service Pilots (U.S.)
Biography
American pilot, British Air Transport Auxiliary, 1942-1945.
Container List
- Clippings
  - Wood-Kelly, Ann (Box 1., Folder 1)
  - Krantz, Judith (Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1971-1996 (Folder 3)
- Flyers - Aero Club (Folder 4)
- Photographs (Folder 5)
- Subject file
  - Air Transport Auxiliary
    - General. Remembrance Sunday, 1992 November 8, 50th anniversary of U.S. women joining ATA (Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1942-1946 (Folder 7)
    - Flyers (Folder 8)
    - Old log books and flight records - primary and secondary (Folder 9)
    - Reunion file - Manchester, 1983 October 5-9 (Folder 10)
  - Federation Aeronautique Internationale. Includes assorted materials (Folder 11)
  - Women Airforce Service Pilots, WWII. Includes materials from the ATA reunion at Santa Fe, New Mexico, 1979 August (Folder 12-13)
- Miscellany (Folder 14)
- Miscellany. Includes materials relating to a proposal to produce a documentary of the contribution of women to the development of aviation, BBC documentary, to the contribution of Jackie Cochran, and some photographs (Box 2., Folder 1)
- Correspondence
  - AWW (Folder 2)
  - Air Transport Auxiliary (Folder 3-6)
- Mailing list - Fundraiser file (Folder 7)
- Obituaries (Folder 8)
- Diaries of Ann Wood-Kelly
  - 1943 January 4-June 7 (Folder 9)
  - 1944 March 17-August 15 (Folder 10)
- Letters of Ann Wood-Kelly
  - 1942 May 10-December 25 (Box 3., Folder 1)
  - 1943 January 4-June 3 (Folder 2)
  - 1943 September 19 - 1944 March 17 (Folder 3)
  - 1943 September 19 - 1944 March 13 (Folder 4)
  - 1944 March 17-August 15 (Box 4., Folder 1)
  - 1944 October 13 - 1945 March 21 (Folder 2)
  - 1944 October 13 - 1945 April 13 (Folder 3)
  - 1945 March 2-April 13 (Folder 4)
  - 1945 May 4-November 1 (Folder 5-6)
- Incremental Materials (Box 5)
  This addition to the collection has not yet been described. Please let the Hoover Institution Archives know if you would like to see this material described.